<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ming zefei&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ming zefei&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 19:22:06 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mingzefei.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Determining Model Parameter Sensitivity Using Sensitivity Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/sensitivity_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 19:22:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/sensitivity_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Sensitivity analysis quantifies the impact of various factors on a model&amp;rsquo;s output. When a model has multiple undetermined parameters, these parameters can be analyzed to identify key parameters that significantly affect the model&amp;rsquo;s results. Targeting these highly sensitive parameters for identification can effectively improve the model&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and reliability, especially for complex models with numerous parameters.
Main Sensitivity Analysis Methods Local Sensitivity Analysis Local sensitivity analysis focuses on the impact of small changes in input parameters around a specific point on the model output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Project Organization</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/sci_proj_organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 21:10:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/sci_proj_organization/</guid>
      <description>A complete scientific project involves multiple aspects, including data, code, and paper reports. Organizing these elements effectively contributes to project management, reproducibility, backups, and traceability.
Based on practical experience, here is a project organization method inspired by the work of Mario Krapp/semic-project and Joshua Cook.
This method is suitable for the following types of projects:
 Core code written mainly in Python; Paper reports primarily written in LaTeX and Markdown; Version control using Git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Plotting</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/scientific_plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 16:07:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/scientific_plotting/</guid>
      <description>Some Principles  Divided into schematic diagrams representing concepts and data charts representing results. Data Charts  Prioritize using position to represent quantity, followed by length and area. Try to avoid pie charts (unless it&amp;rsquo;s essential to show proportions). Color is not the first choice (gray is very misleading; viridis is recommended). Use three-line tables.   Schematic Diagrams  Illustrations are better than engineering drawings or photographs.   Image Formats  Bitmaps are safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siesta Install</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/siesta_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 23:03:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/siesta_install/</guid>
      <description>the best way to install siesta (I think) We have prepared recipes to install Siesta with it. Setup is simple. You need at least to install the miniconda framework (provide more details) and then do: conda install -c conda-forge siesta to install a serial Siesta executable (current version is 4.1.5). To install a parallel version, you need to use, depending on your choice of parallel environment: conda install -c conda-forge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Su Shi&#39;s Xuzhou Flood Control from the Perspective of Systems Methodology</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/su_shi_xuzhou_flood_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 21:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/su_shi_xuzhou_flood_control/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article originated from a major assignment for the course &amp;ldquo;Research Methods in Systems Engineering.&amp;rdquo; The initial requirement was to write a report combining research direction and course content. Later, the restriction on research direction was lifted, leading to this impromptu article. Introduction Xuzhou has a recorded history of over four hundred floods (References 1, 2). Flood control and disaster relief have been frequently carried out. However, local people</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:55:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Origin of the Website Name &amp;ldquo;Ming Zefei (明泽飞)&amp;rdquo; was my nickname during middle school, derived from &amp;ldquo;Yueyang Tower Notes&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;The spring is mild and the scenery is bright, the waves are calm without disturbance, the light from above and below, all is one vast expanse of blue.&amp;rdquo; Sometimes I also rewrite it as &amp;ldquo;Ming Zefei (明则非</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 23:03:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>test level 2 test level 3 Hi~</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latex2Word Conversion Tool</title>
      <link>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/latex2word_en/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingzefei.github.io/en/posts/latex2word_en/</guid>
      <description>From LaTeX to Word: An Automated Conversion Tool LaTeX is commonly used in academic and technical fields for document typesetting, especially for handling equations and cross-references. Since LaTeX files are plain text, they are easy to manage, migrate, and control via versioning systems. However, in day-to-day work, supervisors or colleagues who are unfamiliar with LaTeX often require Word documents for easier collaboration and review. To simplify this process, I developed a tool that automatically converts LaTeX documents into Word format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
